so it's a little convoluted but um it
really it really does work and it's the
best way that I found to get around coup
pets go hack on things you're not
supposed to yeah what go find ACC on
third leverage the third party trust
relationship best part of acing when you
can just you know critical thing right
oh yeah
[Music]
dude all righty y'all I've been telling
you for the past couple weeks about
threat Locker detect right bunch of cool
logging bunch of cool remediation
methods that that built in right into
that Automation in the threat Locker
detect system but at the end of the day
there's nothing quite like having a
human in the loop for these sort of
incidents and back when I was a a
consultant you know one of the
techniques that we would use pretty
often was if we had a team that was
pretty active in incident response like
they were fighting us as we were trying
to get into the systems um we would just
switch to Knights because nobody feels
like getting their butt out of bed and
going to the computer and fighting off
the red teamer right in the middle of
the night um and so that that worked a
lot of the time but threat lockers got
your back in a situation just like this
as well because they've got a product an
add-on for their threat Locker detect
system called cyber hero manage detect
and response and uh this employs a 247
monitoring service of of cyber Heroes
that are there to fight off attack haers
in your network which one sounds hella
intimidating and two makes sense that
you would want a human in the loop there
um yeah what a lot of people don't
realize too is there's time zones right
so could be the middle of the day for
someone in Asia could be middle of the
night here you know in the US so um it's
really important to have someone 247
kind of working on those systems to
defend it and threat Locker has got your
back with that with their uh MDR product
all right cool let's go back to the
show all right my dude First first day
of full-time bug Bounty and freedom from
the from the 9 to five how are you
feeling I feel good yeah and we got to
announce that I'm the new co-host today
which is pretty sick got to post out
everywhere and it's popping off but no
I'm excited to be here I mean I hope
that I can pull off the goal of finding
a bug today on day one obviously you uh
you pulled me away from the computer for
a little while here today but it's worth
it so yeah man dude I I don't know
what's up this morning but my shoulder
is like hecked up from volleyball last
night dude was like some of the best
volleyball I've ever played like I just
we like the rest of our team wasn't
there so we were actually five versus
six and there's something about being
like five versus six that just makes you
kind of go into over overdrive mode you
know what I'm saying is it like an
actual match like one V one where you
advance or you got a win loss and
everything yeah we we played like three
rounds um like three games to 25 and
then we do it again so it's like six
games in total um and it just
contributes to your overall score but
dude yesterday I was just crushing this
the spikes and it just my arm's feeling
it a little bit today though yeah I was
looking around on the ground cuz I was
was thinking about the Neato we we found
out that both you and I uh like our
Neato as our little fidget uh thing cuz
you were using it in the last episode I
freaking love this thing dude I'm like I
I think got one and uh and literally
like I I saw it and I'm like oh my gosh
this thing is amazing I started playing
with it and I never gave it back to
her they got me like six for Christmas
so that's amazing I don't know what it
is about it like it's definitely a a
really unique feel if I'm sure honestly
we already know a lot our listeners have
either ADHD or some form of autism if if
you need a fidget thing this it's called
Neo it's really interesting it
definitely feels like cooler and better
than any kind of other squish toy it's
also it's also pretty freaking good for
just like um just an a hand exercise too
like like it it'll forearms I kind of
want to do that for getting better grips
in BJJ I was already thinking about that
if I just do it enough but anyways dude
I I rolled for the first time in like a
couple months like two weeks ago and it
just dude I it just so reinvigorated I
gotta I got to get out there I got to
get in the gym for that dude it's walked
behind my uh quarterly goal along with
playing video games and watching more
YouTube so when I hit my quarterly bug
Bounty goal it unlocks all of those
things well I I liked I liked what um
what who was it was it Douglas what
Douglas said is like you know offsetting
your goal um with your like professional
goal with like a no no no there was
James Kettle James Kettle posted about
it he said he said um you should have
like a professional goal and then a
another like a non-professional goal
that you kind of pair so he's like I
want to like get my research in Defcon
or whatever and I also want to like do a
three times body weight deadlift I'm
like oh [__] dude like a three times
body weight deadlift is like pretty
freaking good it's pretty intense yeah I
I've always had really strong legs uh
for me I would try I maybe try to do a
three times body weight or maybe two and
a half times body weight squat or
something but oh my god dude are you
serious that's I don't know if I could
but I think it'd be interesting to try
yeah for sure yeah deadlift is
definitely better for me my legs are a
little weak but uh but the back kind of
makes up for it so yeah nice anyway all
right so so we did our we we did a
little little off track right right in
the beginning um we got some news today
a little bit of stuff from me a little
bit of stuff from you and then we're
going to talk about um web header stuff
which uh yeah it seems like you're very
prepared on Joseph yeah we'll talk about
that in a little bit but I'm gonna uh
play as a listener maybe so we'll okay
we we um you know Joseph is is new to
the to the co-host thing and we had the
doc sectioned out and he like did all of
his throrough research on the news
section and then I was like so what do
you think of the the web headers section
and he's like the who what section so
yeah I will say listen I've been a guest
on critical thinking I and I've Ted for
one or two episodes in and everyone all
of the stuff's in the news section it's
all just been right there there's been
no main content so all good man it
happens plus you know I'm I'm used to
just yapping about client side stuff so
I get it all right let me let me hit the
first news item then uh this was just a
really like Feelgood Feelgood story that
I saw um this is from uh I grabbed this
one actually from LinkedIn uh from
Dustin Kirkland and he posted about uh
an article entitled a proud dad's Tale
of Two bug hunting daughters in their
responsible disclosure and when I saw
this dude I was like oh my heart is so
warmed and I was I was reading to
through here and his daughters found two
bugs on the like Al controls aspect of
Google one was like a um you know you
could reuse those like uh codes that you
give to the child to unlock the device
yeah and then the other one was like on
on their like chomecast or Google TV
they just mashed the home button and
they bypassed the parental controls it
just put them right into the parent
account which is like totally nuts yeah
yeah when you sent me that and I clicked
on it first of all the picture the
header picture is like so cute so
hopefully people either tune in to the
YouTube channel and we have our producer
add that in there or they go to the blog
post but um but yeah I mean obviously we
have young kids both you and I and so
that just warms the heart but yeah
totally impressive I mean and they both
got paid like no better way to uh s them
up for financial success from throwing
That Into You know the Roth IRA as like
a eight-year-old oh yeah and then and
for sure and then what did like I want
to say down here at the end where did
she say uh she said first yeah oh was it
the first daughter that was like I want
to invest it in my in the stock bar yeah
she says I asked her what did want to do
with it and she says invested in the
stock market dad and I'm just like could
you imagine like they're Rising them
well that's for sure so cute man so cute
and yeah I think it's I think it's
really cool to share the hacking stuff
with your kids you know um I know that
I've I've hacked with with my with my
kid and uh it's been a nice experience
um at least to just be able to talk
about like yeah I know a little bit
about hacking you know even if it's not
your thing it's still cool to be able to
say like yeah I understand what my dad
does and and uh and can talk about it a
little bit and say they have some
experience with it yeah yeah so with my
oldest daughter she's eight but I think
it was probably when she was seven she
told me that at school to log into some
app they or some website they use they
type in their uh classroom's number like
either their classroom number or their
teacher's name or something but yeah she
told me that instead she typed in our oh
yeah they typed in their classroom
number but instead she typed in our
phone number and there wasn't even
enough digits for it it was like six
digits instead of or 10 or whatever
phone numbers are and it brought up
somewh like a different class and she
could see other students information in
there and when she got home and told me
this I like just lit up I was so pumped
and told her that she had found her
first bug and made a big deal out of it
and then whenever hacker one had like
the family kind of event uh in Orlando
last January they were down there and
she was going around telling all the
other bug hunters and telling all the
staff about the bug she found I would
have a retell the story so dude that's
so cute man yeah the those kids oriented
apps are like Wicked insecure sometimes
and I get it because you got to like
make it easy enough for like a kid to be
able to log in and stuff like that but
like also why don't you just not put all
the kids pii at risk yeah when it's when
it's School related it's yeah yeah and
and and I guess like I don't know if
you're like a motivated attacker trying
to go after kids or something like that
maybe you could figure it out but most
of the time you're not even going to see
it unless you've got a kid and you're
like oh yeah they're logging into this
portal or whatever so I don't know but
it it's definitely little bit insecure I
have to say most of those kid oriented
apps that I've seen yeah I mean all the
different stuff for like kid Sports and
for like their fundraisers and all those
I mean I've probably put our information
in I don't know 20 different sites that
I'm
terrified that are like very vulnerable
very
insecure yeah solid dude all right what
you what have you got on your side you
just want to talk about H1 and BC pent
tests yeah so I put down on this news
list just for the listeners um because I
actually hadn't heard you or Joel
mention it too much it might have been
mentioned in passing but both one and
Bug crowd have a notion of pintest I
don't they've kind of iterated and
changed Through The Years hacker one
pintest are pretty cool they're like in
standard and then premium um you don't
get paid for findings on those I
remember there were some on bugout in
the past I don't know if it still works
this way where you could get paid a flat
fee and then you also got paid for the
vulnerabilities which is pretty cool and
that's how um and I guess just yeah as
an addendum to that not only are there
hacker one a buod pin test but also
Google will sometimes do research grants
yeah where it's similar you get paid
flat fee but you still get um paid for
all of the bugs that you submit and you
have to go in and enable that on your
profile so if anybody has is interested
in that go to your Google Bug Hunter
profile and make sure you enable it that
you're open to it yeah yeah yeah and so
you have to like go in there on bug
hunters. google.com go to your profile
scroll down and I think there's like a
little toggle button that says like
enable research grants and I'm like dang
that that should be public man like like
or that should be on by default like
like that would be great if people just
all of a sudden like boom here's some
money in your bank now go hack on this
yeah exactly you do have to go and
accept it and all that so yeah yeah um
but yeah there's also some I want to I'm
trying to remember who told me about it
it was another top haacker recently told
me about that they were doing some
pentest I want to say it's with
Integrity I don't know um but it was
$500 flat and you get paid for the bucks
right and I'm like and you know anybody
who's done these pent tests before it's
like I don't know man pentests are such
a different world than bug Bounty it's
like there's just bugs freaking
everywhere very frequently especially if
it's one of their first few yeah exactly
and so and so um yeah to be honest I
think I'd be a little bit more in favor
of like the flat rate plus bounties yeah
rather than just the you know higher
flat rate so yeah and I think a lot of
it depends on like the hours that are
expected there um you know if if it's
kind of like make sure you've tested
everything um you know with like a
baseline pass that's much more
reasonable than like a you know a kind
of lowest rate for a bunch of hours so
yeah yeah for sure yeah dude I've really
enjoyed the Google one too like you and
I both got some research grants with
Google lately and they've just been
they've been really great it's just
they're so fun to work with dude to be
honest like because they will help you
exploit bugs um really really nice
really good yeah very communicative yeah
very easy to work with yeah all right
let let let me jump over to my next news
item which was truffle released a new
um a new article talking about ooth bugs
that affect Millions accounts um
particularly Google's ooth login and I
was clicking through here because I've
been really interested in oath lately
and um uh and we're going to do an
episode on oath in a couple weeks after
this episode airs um but this one was
was interesting uh he he does kind of
break down the specific details of it
but the tldr of it is kind of like if a
startup fails you could register the
domain and an SSO into all these
Services which like there's lot other
ways too not necessarily always failing
it could be they changed their domain
like they bought a new one they migrated
there's lots of maybe other use cases or
other examples there yeah I think the
coolest part about this piece of
research was the proposed fix that they
that they had that where they were um
talking about implementing two IM mu
beautiful uh identifiers in the open ID
connect flow um and I think Google May
is considering this they said at the end
of the day they awarded a
$1,337 bounty and then seems like
they'll be making some changes so I
think that's cool but I think this
really also makes me think of the
episode with um like the top bugs uh
from 2024 from the uh the hackers nogi
mentioned on that episode that they used
a uh like a Dev token to get into an
Azure environment M and then once they
were in the Azure environment they
dumped all the users and then uh looked
at all the domains that were
registerable registerable
registr registerable dude I I swear
sometimes like
ma my English just dies dude um but yeah
they they looked for all the domains
that were that were registerable and
then registered one and then use that to
escalate their privileges so I think
that whole I don't know man I don't know
what I think about that concept because
I I think it goes a little bit outside
the realm of like normal bug Bounty flow
um but man the impact is high a lot of
times so yeah yeah yeah it stood out to
me that this is often not I mean
companies where this would be impactful
are already defunct
right yeah ex who's who's gonna pay you
for this but but at the same time there
is impact there because like um they
mentioned this thing you know millions
of people's data is accessible through
these third party SAS providers honestly
it's a little bit of like a SAS security
or I guess maybe Cloud security issue
right because um with the single sign on
once you get access to the account you
can get access to everything else and
yeah I really Lov that part of nagle's
bug and it actually makes me wonder but
also probably believe that other
username disclosures might actually have
slightly more impact if there's
something like this possible so yeah
yeah and and I think the way that this
would apply to bug Bounty is is like you
said you know the the companies that are
being like attacked here mostly what
they're talking about here is is
personal user information and
information that are in those systems
right but um I think that it's most
applicable in the way that ngly did it
right which is you have XYZ company uh
that you're that you're attacking right
and XYZ company contracts Out to ABC
company ABC company goes under right you
you grab the domain and then single sign
on into like some part of XYZ company
the first company and then get access to
like their internal slack or their jira
or whatever um but but to be able to get
that level of insight one you have to
know what companies this this company's
Contracting with right and then you've
also got to understand um you know what
systems that that contracting company
will have access to on your target
company so there's a lot of Recon pretty
heavy Recon that needs to go into place
there but I could definitely see this
being super useful for those targets
where it's like hey get this this you
know get this flag that's in this like
deep embedded system and we don't care
how you do it as long as you get the
flag you get the money and then you kind
of go through this route especially if
they're using some sort of like like if
they're using OCTA or something there's
no doubt there are lots of nonemployee
accounts in there whereas when you think
about something like Google workspace
all the I think like every user is going
to definitely have the exact same you
know uh domain name as a part of their
email address but then there are lots of
systems like Azure or OCTA or whatever
where there are going to be a lot of
guest users like you said contractors
that have different domain names at the
end and then they can actually log in
and those with those expire then of
course you could hijack them so yeah
it's a little interesting I wonder I'm
looking at all this now and I'm I'm
wondering let's say for example we have
a company domain.com that that went you
know unregistered right and we we take
over an account on there is there any
way for us to see what users they had in
that Google Suite organization in the
past because if there was then you'd
have a much easier time saying like Okay
I'm just going to register all of the
users that belong to this company and
then try to use all of those users to
log into all of these systems right you
got sort of like a many to many sort of
thing do like a wild card I'm pretty
sure there's some way to set up like
wild card email stuff where you receive
everything that comes to anyone then you
would be able to slowly know who was
there because they probably register for
webites and they're going to get like or
marketing material so you able to see
who they go to that's a great idea yeah
yeah and then and then you'll see okay
you know slack got an update or
something like that like hm that's a
great idea I like that huh dang it dude
we got to release this on the podcast
now we have a week we have a week to go
look look it up now shoot dude shoot we
got to start recording further in
advance good [__] dude yeah we can maybe
I'm actually I'll just DM you
yeah all good all right what you got
next on your list um yeah so let me pull
back up the show
notes um yeah so I tweeted something um
just literally one sentence so most of
you probably saw it on your Twitter
because for some reason it resonated
with a ton of people I just tweeted that
AI agent security is a massive industry
that's being slept on yeah just blew up
it blew up yeah it got 118,000 views and
already has 1,000 likes and 400
bookmarks um and similar to I think like
it resonated with people in the same way
that I wrote a blog post early last year
like February of last year about uh the
required security architecture changes
to make AI agents secure and
specifically you know I got into the
details of like I think we needed to be
like delegated or childlike system
because when there's a human in the loop
if the AI wants to pay somebody like you
don't want it just throwing your money
out the window right you want to be able
to approve it or if it wants to send an
email or read emails potentially like
sensitive ones then we need some sort of
like way to approve that and then I also
think we need some like really smart
people working on the architecture side
of things like similar to like how Apple
Cloud or apple AI Cloud um they released
that extremely in-depth architecture and
they open sourced it so people could
critique it because they want it to be
secure I think you know when agents are
executing code and stuff the sandboxes
have to be like locked tight especially
as as they potentially get really really
intelligent and we need like AI safety
controls there too um and so in in
general I think there's going to be like
an off layer like an off um Z layer
where it's like you know just because
this AI can use the browser should they
be able to send requests to gmail.com or
should they be able like I almost wonder
I was thinking about this this is like
some big Alpha I think there's a
potential solution there at the DNS
level so like I think that you could
potentially have like almost firewall
like restrictions or just like a
specific you know AI agent safe DNS
support from Cloud Player or something
where it's like at 3. 3.5.5 or something
and and like that's specifically for
sandboxes the AI are interacting in they
won't let them do certain stuff but
anyways I don't know but my my whole
point in bringing this up for the
podcast is we've got a lot of really
smart listeners that are extremely
intelligent and I think they should lean
into the niche of if they're interested
in it how am I going to hack AI agents
in the future because there's going to
be a bunch of new companies that are
going to get bug b any programs that are
offering AI agent type support how can I
hack on my existing programs which are
already implementing AI agents on the
backside like what kind of bug could be
there and then if people like building
stuff like how can I build some sort of
like AI agent security product whether
that off layer or other stuff so I just
wanted to bring that up because I think
it's it's um blowing up in the industry
and it's on people's mind there's a lot
of that man yeah for sure and it's
definitely like like we were talking
about before the episode ran you know I
think it's it's a space where it's a
very good Niche you know if you if you
are looking for an area where you want
to specialize in in um in hacking stuff
yeah uh and you just want to make good
money on that you want to be a high-
paid consultant that sort of thing or or
you know there's an episode that I'm
thinking about doing which I won't you
know give away too much on but
essentially it's an episode around like
the what I call the uh ajx Chapman
method which is you like deep specialize
on one specific thing and how do you do
that and what areas would be a good
place to specialize I think this makes
the list you know because um whenever
you see weaponized uh agents you know
agents that have functionality to them
that that are of the ability to take
action you know that's a specialized
technology um that you have to know how
to attack so so I mean let me ask you
this dude what what are what do you
think are
like okay let me just draw the
correlation back to the the ajx Chapman
sort of thing right you know people hit
Alex Chapman up when they see a headless
browser yep headless browser xsc you got
to get it exactly you get that sort of
headless browser type environment so
what is the the user agent Chrome right
of these agent things what are the
things that you should see uh that make
you say okay hey uh I should get this to
an expert or I should Deep dive on this
because there's more functionality here
that I need to know how to attack at
like a deeper level yeah does that
question make sense yeah it does that's
basically the question I was asking
Johan in that episode if people want to
go back and listen to that but like in
general it's just like if it can do
anything interesting with data or tools
that's why that's what I find super
interesting and I think that that level
of um functionality is a is a
target-rich environment because um it
it's it is kind of annoying to hack
sometimes because you have to convince
the system to use the payload you want
to use super freaking annoying yeah but
uh also Port saker's Labs on that are
really good right it's like you're
telling an agent to call a tool with a
payload and you can tell it to use a
apostrophe or you can tell it to use
open and close square brackets you can
tell it to like use other users IDs
right there's like a there's kind of a
rich attack surface there um but yeah I
mean I think it's a strong Niche even if
you don't like interacting with llms
like I don't want everyone to think like
oh you know I don't want to be the llm
hacker guy and it and llms can be
annoying because of the non-determinism
there but I think in this in this AI
agent security space we need people who
are like working on like kind of the
sandbox and like the sandbox escapes we
need people who are like tackling The
Prompt injection and gel break side of
things we need people who are like
thinking through the AI safety thing so
I think that there's a lot of different
areas you can specialize in um but yeah
in general I would say if there's a
chatbot or an AI feature that has like a
lot of tools or like some interesting or
deep tools and if the D and if the tools
have access to any kind of data like you
just when you're chatting with chat Bots
ask like hey what do you know about me
what can you tell me about myself
because if it has a lot of information
about you then someone could leak that
probably about you with certain
different
techniques there there was a challenge
we were given by a Target recently and I
I I think the way that they outlined
what they were looking for with these AI
attacks was super good they were like
hey you know it needs to start with some
sort of indirect prompt injection so um
there has to be some tool tool that is
grabbing your data as the attacker and
then putting it into the prompt right so
you know then they've got an array of
tools that they can do that with and
then from there you need to establish
control of the llm prompt right and then
once you've established control of the
llm prompt you need to either XYZ right
you either get persistence on the system
you you um affect the user's data in a
negative way in a way that's un not
undoable you know that causes permanent
dat loss or permanent data effect um or
leak their data yeah yeah or leak the
data back out right so I think that's
that's a good a good like just quick and
easy three-step process right establish
some uh reasonable method for prompt
injection right you know indirect prompt
injection or prompt injection establish
control of the prompt right and and um
you know gain control of the llm and
then utilize that control to either leak
or affect user data or gain persistence
in the llm moving forward yeah yeah yeah
good stuff Prett pretty solid um Okay
cool so uh dude let me let me hop into
this next this next dude now I'm all
hype on AI stuff now I gotta change I
gotta change uh well actually dude since
we're talking about AI stuff what is
this rank thing that you had from Bishop
Fox yeah so um I'm sure most people know
of operator I found out before the
episode that you're also friends with
him in real life which is cool dude he
rocks man but um so yeah he wrote this
uh thing you all can find in the show
notes it's called rank but spelled with
an i so it's AI uh with in the middle of
the word rank um and so one thing you
often want to do when you're hacking in
general it's like what asset should I
look at first right which domain is most
interesting which payload is most likely
to work they're like humans kind of
figure out you know um what we're going
to do first by kind of ranking them in
our head and then just like going down
that list with AI sometimes that's hard
to get them to like um that's not hard
to get them to you can just ask them to
list them but it's hard to get uh AI
output to be ranked in a meaningful way
based on a specific heris that you want
and to not repeat itself and that sort
of thing and so they found some cool
ways to I haven't dug into how all the
different ways they use them but they
wrote um open source project where you
can have ai rank a list of anything and
so I think for the security implications
there are pretty cool the ones I just
mentioned you know ranking the best
payload to we use or the most likely to
use or the website that's most likely to
be vulnerable Etc there probably a lot
of different use cases here but I think
you went to the talk where they actually
use this to find some bugs with called
patch perfect right yeah it was it was
really cool when you when this showed up
in my docs because one I'm like buddies
with Caleb he's like he's like uh I knew
him even even before the security
Community we just met through a mutual
friend and um and then it was It was
kind of crazy I don't know if I've
talked about the story on the Pod before
but like I met him through a mutual
friend right and my mutual friend was
like Hey you know you're a hacker he's a
hacker and I'm like okay cool yeah sure
and then I meet him and he's like this
super badass dude like uh and it's so
because like there's so many people out
there that are like yeah I'm a hacker
and they like you know they work in
security and it's like you know okay
cool you know you are a hacker but it
doesn't mean that you're doing like
hands on the keyboard you know PC or
GTFO popping [__] all day every day sort
of hack right um that is definitely
Caleb you know and so like when I met
him I was like oh [__] he's the real
deal um and so anyway I I you know we've
got a local conference here in Richmond
called rvac and uh you know Kayla being
the inspiration that he is decides to
support the local local conference and
present his talk there um and so so I
was there you know just chilling
watching this this talk and uh it was
really good it was it it was entitled
patch perfect harmonizing with llms to
find security vs which I loved you know
because I'm a big I'm a musical Musical
Boy Pitch Perfect Pitch a fantastic
movie we listen to that soundtrack for
like years after it came out freaking
good man I'm like I'm I'm a little bit
scared of that movie because if I listen
if I watch it again it's gonna get all
the ear bugs I'm just going to be
singing non-stop for the past or for the
foreseeable future but um the talk was
really good in in how they use sort of
like this ranking sort of thing to
identify uh the most likely functions in
a in a um binary diff of a patch that
contain the vulnerability and give the
the researcher that's trying to reverse
a patch a head start on where the
vulnerability lies yeah that's really um
and and the results were pretty
impressive like they're able to get it
down um to like 10% of all the the diff
functions with accuracy the fun that
vulnerability isin this top 10es you
know 90% of time so definitely lots of
good um lots of good applications for
this across security and it's nice to
have a tool that that automatically does
it yeah that's legit you want to tell us
about this uh gift card research oh yeah
okay cool yeah so um our boy
w2w uh a a member of the full-time
Hunters Guild by the way shout out to my
man um dropped some research called gift
card security research and I just wanted
to to um to shout this one out we'll um
we'll link it in the description as
always but let me go ahead and share my
screen as well for those for those folks
on YouTube um This research was awesome
uh because once again it's just a time
when somebody says hey I'm going to
research this specific b class or this
specific Niche and they do it across a
lot of targets and they record the
results I'm such a sucker for that stuff
man that's what that's the stuff the
stuff that
that freaking bug Bounty reports
explained does on their like premium
newsletter subscription where you'll
just get like these super data rich
analyses on types of vulnerabilities and
it's just so insightful into the way
that you should look at these B classes
um yeah you apply sometimes in your own
life like with the credit card research
so oh oh 100% yeah and and um it's very
applicable and definitely worth whatever
I pay for bug Bounty reports explained
premium for sure um but this one w2w
gives us for free and he says I acquired
30 plus gift cards on This research and
revealed nine vulnerabilities by
unlocking new features which granted me
$6,500 um and let me see how many bugs
he's got here I think nine different
bugs um and there were three primary vul
classes that popped out of this there
was race condition there was HTML
injection or xss and uh idor and I just
wanted to Echo this as well because my
personal experience has really um
aligned with this research that uh
anytime I've bought gift cards there's
either a race condition or an idor I
don't know what it is but there just
always is every time um yeah and and so
uh I think that's a pretty Target Rich
um and attack Vector Rich environment
and you can sometimes get a gift card
for like five bucks so it's definitely
worth the investment yeah I mean anytime
you can get access to like a little more
scope a few more API calls and like
working ones too right if you have the
gift card you're actually going to be
able to actually purchase something
you'll be able to actually enable it it
gives you access to a bunch of like
either new domains or paths that are
actually working for you yeah yeah for
sure and then so you know those are the
three main V types that he he found um
the specific research and then I wanted
to also just shout out this last tip at
the very end he doesn't he doesn't talk
about this too much in the actual um
article but he says at the end final
thoughts he says ensure you enable out
of scope logging and all MIM types in
your uh mum proxy uh to catch the
checkout finalization request I wasted
quite a few gift cards to learn this
lesson it doesn't hurt when it's a $5
gift card but it's a big gouch moment
when it's a $50 gift card um so yeah I
totally agree like going through that
full process and just literally
intercepting everything and going
through each request being like is this
the final request is this the final
request you know so that you can race
condition it or something like that um
very important and there's definitely
some gotchas there with the the proxy
trying to let you focus on specific
stuff yeah and I would say a lot of
these um companies that are using gift
cards might be using third parties so
it's it's very smart to enable out of
scope blogging because it could be on
the weird domain it could be on the
third party domain like you don't want
to miss it very common that's one of the
things I love about kaida it's it's a
little bit of a love and hate thing with
that with kaido right now but kaido
doesn't have currently a way to set
logging to none for stuff you can't just
drop requests they get stored right yeah
they always get stored and and you know
that blows up your hard drive space a
little bit but storage is cheap and you
know what is not cheap not having the
piece of information that you need and
so there there have been many times
where I've been like
dude that S3 bucket or like oh man this
this is this functionality is getting
pushed out to a third party how did I do
that and then I went back and I and the
data was there right and I was like
freck yeah so I mean that that alone has
made me several thousand dollars I think
um uh you know just having that force me
to be a little bit more permissive with
what what I'm storing and that's the
same sort of thing we talked about last
year when when mayonnaise came on the on
the Pod where he literally has
never uh not had every single he's never
gotten rid of any piece of data related
to a bug bount Target ever right and
he's just got it all in a big database
and he just does Big Data queries
against it you know and he just uncovers
these Trends across targets and and
across the same Target so definitely
definitely a a useful piece of
functionality I think for sure yeah and
then I think the one last thing we
wanted to mention it's on your list but
I can kick us off on it yeah is that the
um top 10 voting for from portswigger oh
yeah um is now out and not only is it a
huge Treasure Trove of data but our
listeners probably care deeply about who
wins because there's a lot of our
listeners who are on this list right and
so make sure make sure you go out and
support the uh your fellow hackers by
voting for their research if you like it
and um it's a fantastic way to go back
and learn uh what you missed or see what
you missed from um as far as like cool
hacks go from last year absolutely yeah
there are a lot of um uh CBB podcast
guests that have their their data out
here um uh in this up for rating so uh
that's that's pretty rad definitely
definitely like you said a good place to
see the research that you missed great
research that you missed but also just
to support the fellow hacker I can't
help but ask you do you have any idea
why there's one that says do not vote
for the century dude I saw that I just
saw that as I'm scrolling through there
I don't know but dude you know that
haers are going to vot for for sure it's
going to get so many vot don't do that
guys come on don't waste your vote give
some valid research the vote please
that's true um solid all right man cool
so now the time has come to talk about
web headers yeah the topic the topic I
did not know uh what we were even
discussing today so yes I will play the
the ignorant listener and also in
general you know my specialty is not in
frontend stuff it's definitely been
serers side bugs and kind of uh big
fuzzing and then obviously AI of late so
this is stuff that I've been wanting to
dig into and this has given me excuse to
learn about it so um when I don't
understand something the a lot of
listeners probably don't either and so
I'll be sure to ask that yeah dude ask
away and I'll do my best to to
articulate it all um so yeah what we're
talking about today is cross origin
headers which is like a suite of headers
cross origin opener policy cross origin
EMB better policy cross origin research
policy I'm sorry resource policy and um
how these specific headers apply to the
browser and how to get around them and
unfortunately I have to say guys it's
it's rough it's rough out there there's
not a lot of ways to get around these
things um so but I'm going to give you
my best my best takes on it and um uh we
we have a little bit of research from
the the um critic research lab which is
the team that we kind of put together to
try to try to give us cool pieces of of
information about this uh and and also
I'll just kind of you know talk to you
about how these headers are actually
used yeah so question with this Andrew
Lock Link at the top I think you're
going to talk about did you learn
anything new like did you learn any uh
kind of potential bypasses or gadgets as
you went through this yeah so I think
the Andrew Lock article is really which
we'll Link in the in the description but
also just go ahead and and share on the
screen now um it's sort of like a
three-part blog post
on these cross origin headers uh it's
entitled understanding cross origin
security headers so he does part one on
uh Coupe which is the main culprit the
one that we hate uh and then there's
part two on Cross origin uh resource
policy which is an interesting one and
then we've got cross origin and better
policy as well so these are definitely
if you're looking to sort of skill up on
this area um these are great I think
this came out in November of last year
but yeah there was definitely some
things that I learned about here that um
I didn't know before so definitely
definitely worth a read um if you're
trying to skill up there uh but I'll
also try to give you the tldr today yeah
exactly you know um and see how we can
we can do that so um first this this
whole set of headers and this whole
concept is uh related to a browser
concept called cross origin isolation um
and this is a a concept uh that was
recently put into the browsers to kind
of help deal with the Spectre uh attacks
that were happening um that that allowed
you to violate same origin policy um and
if you opt into these cross origin
headers you get some of the features
back that they had to remove to to help
um deal with the Spectre attacks um and
there's a a JavaScript you know window
property called uh cross origin isolated
and it's a Boolean true or false and it
tells us whether in this specific
context are is this this Frame this this
window is it cross origin isolated or
not um so that's that's something that I
didn't even know existed uh but is but
is actually in place what are some
examples for why you would want to not
isolate an origin or what and then when
you would yeah so so if you're trying to
isolate an origin it provides an extra
layer of security but also there are
reasons to not do it right if you need
to communicate with a a different tab um
via like a a window. opener relationship
or something like that via post message
or or whatever then you can't really
isolate yourself because there has to be
a relationship between those two tabs in
the browser context group um and so to
open a new window for you to like log in
or do an offlow or do something and then
it needs to pass something back to the
first tab they could not use this
feature exactly and and that's that's
something you often see with off flows
is like is like um you know you're
handing it off either to a third party
or to a same something on your same site
right which is like you know O.D
domain.com yeah going back to
www.domain.com right the site is the
same but the origin is different
um uh where it starts to get a little
tricky and so the main header that that
that just really tweaks my melon Joseph
like they really just hex up some great
exploits is uh the cross origin opener
policy or Coupe okay so let me let me
sort of let me rant on this one for a
second okay Coupe this son of a badger
is uh really messing up some stuff uh
because what what often happens in when
we're trying to exploit post meage
related bugs which is like one of my
bread and butter vulnerabilities is we
need to open up a new tab because of uh
same sight stuff or xram options right
so we pop open a new tab and then we
send a post message from our attacker
controlled page to our our victim page
right yeah um and the in order for us to
send they have to be in the same browser
context Group which is why we we open it
up and we get a frame reference um and
then we can do frame reference. post
message and that's how we send it this
son of a gun Coupe here sever that frame
reference so whenever I pop up in a new
tab if that new tab you know site.com
sure uh has the coupet and it says Coupe
um same origin or same origin allow
popups then um when I try to access that
window you know that I opened up bya
window. open it's going to say
null it severs that relationship right
yeah yeah so there's no freaking way
Joseph to send a post message to that
page and I have a zero how many bugs do
you have that are are blocked by that
dude it's actually figured out a way
around it um which I'll I'll explain
which is great um but there there this
will really really inhibit a lot of post
message related bugs and but but there
is an upside to this too dude which is
that you can tell companies that don't
want to pay for like third-party Library
vulnerabilities like that have post
message yeah that they have a
remediation method which is they can put
cross origin opener policy on their page
and then there's no way to send a post
message through right and so it's sort
of a double-edged sword right people
paid sometimes because you can yeah yeah
because they have a mitigation you give
a fix yeah exactly um so that it's a
little bit of a double-edged sword in
that regard but um essentially what it
does is it severs the the relationship
between your attacker page and the
victim page uh and there's no way to
communicate um via post message between
those two now let me kind of talk about
the nuances of this this bad boy for a
second okay so one and this is the big
one it only effects top level pages okay
so if you can so let's say you've got a
a vulnerability on www.s.com right yeah
um if you can get www.s.com
iframed into a page that does not have
coups right so let's say you know if
frame. site.com iframe is in wws.com
right right if iframe do.com doeses not
have a coupet then you can do a window.
open to iframe dos. comom and then it
will iframe www.s.com and then you can
send a message from your attacker
control page through through if frame.
site.com to the page yeah exactly and so
even even though www.s.com has the coupe
header it's going to be ignored because
it's not a top level page right um and
so you still will have that frame
reference and can send that data through
um and and so here's the place where I
mean this this is the major the major
workaround that that the team you know
uh the the research lab team that was
kind of talking about um these Concepts
uh shared uh which is that if you can
figure out a way to get it uh iframed in
then that's kind of your best way to
exploit this and uh and I'll just share
from my own personal hacking experience
that it it is easier to get an iframe
injection um you know when you are
dealing with some third-party libraries
right and so oftentimes what will happen
is like a site will have a thirdparty
library It'll like iframe in some like
support page or like some yeah
P or right and then if you can get anss
on that page on that then you can reach
through redirect if you can get it this
is how it works so like You' I'm getting
I'm getting crazy now guys listen
closely because this one's going to be
tricky okay so you get an xss on the on
this the you know support support.com
right right so you you get the xss on
support.com you you iframe that into
your Tacker page right um so now you've
got control of support.com in your
attacker page then you you open up a
window to uh the page that has the the
uh I iframe
support.com and then you reach from your
attacker controlled you know accss and
you reach over through the the page that
you can't into the if frame on the
victim page and then you redirect that
to the page that has the coup headers
that's absurd that's even possible do
you see what I'm saying and then now
yeah because you have the xss it's same
origin so you can do redirects and then
and now you've got the page that has the
coup headers embedded in if frame.
site.com and then you can communicate to
that page via VIA post message and then
pop your xss or whatever so it's a
little convoluted but um it really it
really does work and it's the best way
that I found to get around coup Peters
go hack on things you're not supposed to
yeah well go find EX on third leverage
the third party trust relationship is I
prefer to call it there you go yep and
you're doing it for a responsible reason
and just closing it and it's fine but
yes no I agree I think I think that's
really cool and I'm I'm shocked that I
was able to follow that hopefully the
the listeners can too but yeah basically
on your attacker page if you get xss you
can iframe that support.com and and
influence the iframe of support.com on
the on the company's website which
allows you to redirect it yeah dude
that's great all right dude I'm glad
you're able to track with that I I don't
know if that's you being big brain or my
explanation being sufficient but so some
combination of the two I imag yeah yeah
sense okay so let me mention this other
piece of this okay yep Coupe is also
it's called cross origin opener policy
but it actually has it affects the
opener and the open right so if you can
get a like whatever site.com to open a
pop-up window uh it will also have a
severed relationship if the if the coup
is in place well actually let's let's
Tell The Listener real quick what are
the options for that header the values
yeah okay great thank you great
great great great specification there
okay so there are three values for that
there's same origin which means um only
sites of the same origin can have that
open relationship right their same
origin allows popups which I'll explain
and then there's unsafe none or missing
which is like the default value when
it's not there okay so good it's it's
great if it's missing yeah exactly um so
same origin allow pop-ups is the the
nuanced one okay so essentially what
happens with that one is like you can't
have any
relationship excuse me you can't have
any relationship with the page
beforehand but if that page opens up a
popup to like your attacker controlled
page then that page will have a
reference to the other the page with the
coups um because it's a popup from the
page with the coup headers right so if
you can get it to to pop up a window
then you will be able to access that get
a frame reference to that window via
window. opener okay um so that's another
sort of workaround it's a little bit
more rare for you to be able to get a
popup like that um you kind of need like
a popup injection or maybe there's like
some page where they forgot to do like
um where they had like a like an a tref
you know pointing to it and they didn't
put like no refer or or anything like
that um but if you can get that to
happen then you can be able to trigger
the attack back on that same page that
has the coups does that make sense or am
I it it does a little bit yes I've I've
not I've never even heard of pop-up
injection so yeah well it's it yeah that
I just there's a good reason for that I
just I just invented it on the spot but
um yeah you know controlling where you
know what window or what location site
is popping up it seems pretty it seems
pretty rare like you said I've never
seen Sam site allow pop ups so it's not
really a a very relevant situation um
but I figured I would add that Nuance in
there um just in case cool okay so two
other so that's Coupe pain in the ass
severs the frame relationship solution
is if it has allow pop-ups try to get a
popup and if it doesn't have allow
pop-ups if it's just same origin then
you need to get that page iframed into a
page that that is same origin but does
not have a coupet which is really which
is tricky you know so you got to
understand where your application
segments are and get that if frame
injection and once I I'll just add there
there is no same site setting for this
so it has to be exactly same origin um
and and so my my example was a little
bit flawed it can't be if frame.
site.com it has to be ww.
iframing in www.s.com
um which which does make it more
difficult but was the situation when I
actually exploited it um uh and so
just large companies with a lot of
functionality under a main domains where
you would have to find that yeah exactly
and there there there will be different
application segments as well right where
there's like okay slash whatever is one
app and then SL blah blah blah is
another app right that's right um so
that's the sort of situation we're
looking at
um okay two more headers to go these
would would be a lot less um a lot less
nuanced we have cross origin and better
policy okay this one um this one is kind
of exactly what it sounds like it's a
policy on what can be embedded into the
page okay so the default value for that
is unsafe none or if it's missing then
that's unsafe unsafe none and there's
two other values um require Corp which
I'll explain in just a second and then
credential lists which is any resource
that you have embedded in the page will
be sent with zero cookies you know your
images whatever and this is a little bit
less of a big thing now that we've got
same site cookies that cookies aren't
really sent anyway unless they unless
they are you know top level navigations
yeah um but uh if this is something that
you're running into and you do need to
have um those on there um then you're
you're kind of screwed um so just be
aware of those three values and then
going back to the other one what does
require Corp what does require Corp do
good good question let me let me explain
that so re corpse says any any asset
that is being embedded in this page has
to return the the cross origin resource
policy header okay and if it doesn't
then it's blocked okay and the cross
origin resource policy header unlike
these other two headers EMB better
policy and opener policy which are
embedded on the page this resource
policy uh header has to be embedded on
the asset that is being loaded okay
that's really interesting I feel like
that's a that's a kind of a paradigm
that could be applied like like a meta
Paradigm that could be applied for
security and other places it makes me
think it's like a really neat concept
that you want to like go ahead and um
pre-approve or put on an allow list
things from other places and so what you
do is you put it in the in the body or
the header of the thing that's coming in
it's kind of interesting yeah it's very
thorough it's it's very depends in dep I
just dm'd you a link this is like to um
uh googleusercontent.com um which is
where they like host user content for
Google and you notice there their cross
origin resource policy says says cross
origin which is the most permissive
setting right so there's three settings
same site same origin and cross origin
so this is particularly helpful if you
are looking to prevent an asset that you
have from being embedded on an attacker
controlled page and um there's a
specific class of vulnerabilities that
is all but gone now but but does still
sort of exist called cross site um
xss cross- site script injection okay
yeah and I don't know if you you were in
the like front end game when this class
vulnerability existed but essentially
how this works is on an attacker
controlled page you do a script tag and
you include a dynamically generated
script on the Target website that leaks
data about the current user's
authenticated State and then when it
loads that script into your page you can
do some JavaScript [__] to pull out the
data and and get access to right and so
this kind of got deleted when when same
site lack became the default but um uh
if if the Au is being done off of same
site none cookies and the script is
being dynamically generated off those
cookies then it could be something that
that could still happen so you know
anytime you see dynamically generated
scripts you should be be thinking about
that um but this is the cross origin
resource policy is a great way to
prevent this from happening so you can
take that script add the cross origin
resource header to it and say hey cross
Origins set it to same site or same
origin cross origin is not allowed to
load this this resource and then that
would block that XSI from occurring
because the attacker could not include
your dynamically generated script tag on
their page does that make sense yeah
does the browser just like straight up
refuse it yeah it says no we're not
gonna let them load this resource
because they don't have yeah yeah that's
cool so it's pretty solid yeah okay so
that's so if you implement all three of
those headers correctly then the
JavaScript Boolean cross origin isolated
will be set to True um and then you're
you get access to a bunch of like super
secure timing apis and stuff like that
that you can get access to that that
Spectre was utilizing to leak leak a
bunch of stuff um yeah so I just wanted
to give those to the listeners and kind
of say hey this is kind of what we've
got uh as far as these cross origin
headers go un like cross origin EMB
better policy and cross origin resource
policy are not super helpful um for
attacker but understanding the nuances
of Coupe are absolutely necessary um and
I think that workaround that the
research lab came up with with like
getting it embedded into a page is super
helpful for exploting these sort of
scenarios yeah I mean I doubt there are
very many people who have figured that
out and so there's probably a lot of
those lying around where it seemed
unexploitable but there actually is now
a path to exploitation yeah yeah so
shout out to to the the team I'm it
worms the heart a little bit to see some
some uh some good research coming out of
the research lab already um it is an
investment we're doing and uh we've
already seen I think several vules get
popped from the the research lab and
then also this this nice piece of
research getting pumped out to the Pod
so appreciate you guys on the on the
research lab 100% um okay dude hang in
there I got two more headers I want to
tell you about okay yeah okay so these
are not related to cross origin stuff
but I just kind of wanted to since we're
talking about web headers I kind of
wanted to like throw these in there just
as a bonus okay the next two are service
worker allowed and X content type
options okay so I'm glad you have
service worker allowed on there I know
you have mentioned service worker stuff
a lot in the past and I'm not you know
super up to date on like how it works
and like what vums are possible there
but you see it all over the place these
days so I'm curious um yeah what you
have to say about this so service
workers for those of you that aren't
familiar is essentially a way for you to
I'm going to explain this from such an
attacker perspective like literally what
I was about to say was a way for you to
gain persistence in the browser right
service workers are not that service
workers are something to help with
caching and like a bunch of other stuff
like that in the browser but from an
attacker perspective from a hacker's
perspective it's a way for you to gain
persistence in a victim's browser okay
so the way this typically works is you
have to have file upload you have to be
able to upload a JS file and you've got
to be able to upload an HTML file or
have an xss okay cool um and once you do
that you can register a service worker
and that service worker is scoped to
whatever path you have the the the JS
file and the the xss on so if you're you
know if your JS file is under you know
slite SL asset upload then your service
worker is only going to be able to
access slight as upload and affect the
the pages that are being loaded in the
victim's browser thereafter at those
paths okay yep yep um but it's pretty
cool if you can get it installed at
slash then you just essentially have
persistent xss on every single page in
the browser which is yeah I was going to
say I guess that means that many service
workers are probably implemented at root
because they need to be able to run
across a majority of the website yeah so
if you're able to attack a service
worker that's a really um interesting
scope too because if you're able to to
hijack um then I imagine there's a lot
of stuff you can do there I do know that
it's a little bit tricky and I do know
that the research lab is doing some
research on the that right now um but
very very ripe scope um however so you
know that path thing really kind of gets
into the gets in gets to become a
problem because it's not that rare that
we can upload like a Javascript file or
an HTML file to a Target right that's
that's pretty standard um but you know
it's normally at some like obscure path
that has our ID in it if we register a
service worker there then it doesn't
really do anything right um uh and so
there's this header that's very
interesting called service worker
allowed and it's an HTTP response header
that contains a path that the the
service worker should be scoped to so
even if your JS file is at like you know
SL asset SL user my user id/ whatever.
JS if you can figure out a way to return
the service worker allow header and say
service worker allowed colon slash right
then um it will the browser just trusts
it it trusts it and it will give the
service worker uh permission to access
anything under slash cool right which is
which is great so here's the here's
where the rubber meets the road on this
one I just want to make people aware of
this uh because I know fron has done a
lot of really cool stuff and there in
maton as well um related to using
service workers to leak like private um
like signed uh signed head or send like
quer parameters to access like a
specific file and that sort of thing um
and I think this is really help helpful
for those sort of scenarios but it's
pretty rare that you can control an HTP
response header um and there's two sort
of main configurations where I can think
that that that would be happening and
that is with crlf injection right if you
can get a crlf injection then you can in
insert this header um and get the xss
and generate the JS file which is pretty
rad um or more likely in a scenario
where the app allows you to configure a
reverse proxy back to your own site okay
and I wanted to sort of shout out this
specific um functionality in Shopify um
called app proxies uh and essentially it
allows you to do just that proxy a
specific path on a store that you've
installed an application on back to your
website um and and so you know typically
you could return the service worker
allow header and that would allow you to
register a service worker which would
gain you control of the whole my Shopify
uh website but they have a list of
disallowed headers that can come through
this reverse proxy and service worker
allowed is on that so if anybody can
figure out a way to smuggle a service
worker allowed header through this app
proxy then that's a really cool piece of
scope um and any other scenarios any
other targets where there's like an app
proxy like functionality where you're
doing a reverse proxy um uh there is a a
really ripe attacks scenario there with
with service workers um being able to
take over that whole origin not just the
origin that you're scoped to uh for the
reverse proxy so why does Shopify have
this if you don't want I don't know man
I I I'll give a full disclaimer you know
umic I would be careful reporting bugs
on this scope you know um I know that
there are some some weird quirks with
this specific piece of scope but I just
wanted to use it as an example because
um uh
it's it's pretty funky functionality
yeah and I think there's a lot of areas
where that can cause problems yeah I'm I
was just trying to think through like if
I understood why Shopify added it then I
would be able to like kind of update my
mental model for what other companies
what other programs would maybe have a
similar functionality yeah I think you
know Shopify is really built on plugin
so I think you see this type of
functionality in any area where um you
know there's app hosting or there's like
third party plugins that really need to
be seamless integrated into the main app
those sort of scenarios where youan
stuff like that yeah yeah lasan might
have something similar I want to say I
saw something
on so yeah um those those bigger those
giant apps you know often have this
functionality sort of buried in there
related to the app functionality yeah
definitely all right cool last one dude
my my throat is getting a little
scratchy again I don't know I've had
this cold for like a week uh it just
won't go
away yeah I heard I heard it come
through or twice but you've been good
yeah all right so last one here x
content options um has one one available
um sort of parameter that you can give
it which is no sniff okay and have you
heard of this one before Joseph do you
know what this one does I don't but I
have seen it many many times yes so
essentially what it does is uh the
browser will attempt to sniff the
content type of the page that is being
returned if a content type header is not
provided
okay and so this one says don't freaking
do that is what it says right um because
that a lot of xss occur from can can
occur from that sort of thing content
type sniffing or even as we've learned
recently um character set sniffing can
cause a lot of issues so this says don't
do that just just don't okay and um I
just wanted to get tell the community
about this one little Nuance that I
stumbled upon um not too long ago which
is that if you repeat the content type
option header twice let's say you've got
a CRF injection and your injection is
below the content type um options header
and below the content type header right
so you can't overwrite those two headers
what you can do is you can add another X
content types header with a with a
invalid value and the browser will be
like ah dude there's two there's two
content type options headers uh what do
I do I'm I'm gonna I'm gonna sniff I got
I got a sniff you know the browser is
just really eager to sniff for some
reason
um and so if you provide two of these
content type options headers it will
actually discard both of them uh and
allow the browser to actually sniff the
the content type from the data that's
being returned so it's a pretty amazing
Yeah man so this uh this content type
options header it's really funky the
world why would a browser just drop it
if there's two it's like just take one
at least that's what they do for most
other headers but I think this is also a
really like interesting area of research
where this one content type options
header behaves this way if other headers
that sort of have a similar
functionality um so that's that's
something that's on the research list
for the research lab and and maybe the
community can kind of poke at it as well
yeah it's so easy to now I think you
mentioned this to me recently to have ai
spin up like little dock containers of
things that like you know servers that
respond in weird ways for example it'd
be really interesting to like have it do
that with a bunch of different duplicate
headers and see how browsers respond
yeah absolutely definitely a cool cool
and really easily done piece of research
I think like that could easily be
knocked out in eight hours and you could
like write something up and it'd be
really on the podcast it'd be great
people let us know yeah send it send it
to us guys drop it in the cool research
section if you do it um and we'll cover
it on the Pod um okay um one little
thing that I just wanted to close with
dude so you've seen the refer header
right that's like super common of course
a million times yeah dude I I i' I've
always thought there was something funky
about the refer header like I I
sometimes you know there's like seesar
protections or whatever and you're like
checking something and it says oh you
know don't have their refer header and
then I type referer and I give it a
refer and it says don't have the refer
header and I'm like ah I misspelled
referer you know there's only one R
right no no there's two RS dude refer
the the refer header that is always sent
in the browser every time you make a
request contains a misspelling of the
word referrer referrer is spelled r e f
r r e r and the one that the browser
actually sends is r e f r e r yeah I
don't know I I came across this randomly
someone else mentioned it as like a
little tidbit or like did you know about
web security like a few years ago but
it's really funny and mind-blowing I
love like any kind of little quirks of
old systems I think about that a lot
with video games I know a lot of our
listeners probably game but I think it's
really like just neat and a really cool
byproduct of the fact that some small
Dev team made some decision 15 years ago
and now like two you know two million
people are like playing this game where
they're over optimizing to find that one
item that the developer didn't think
about when they actually added an
attribute that was overpowered or
something you know like I think it's
really cool to have those Downstream
effects and it feels similar here it's
like some developer misspelled it and at
some point it was way too uh embedded in
all the systems to like roll back yeah
so the it makes me feel good like you
know these people these core people that
built the whole this is what I'm talking
about like when when I said on the Pod a
couple weeks ago like the people that
built all these crazy specs and these
cool like crazy protocols and stuff like
that they're just humans just like you
know like there's no need to be so
intimidated from all this if some some
bro in his base built this protocol you
can figure it out in like you know 10
times as much time he as he took so it's
not going to be beyond your grasp you're
not just incapable of of learning this
you can it just takes time so and people
like those Bros misspell the word refer
and then the whole internet has to use
this mis misspelling for the rest of the
time the internet exists so yeah I feel
like usually the stuff that's like hard
to understand or confusing is mostly due
to like naming conventions or like the
fact that our brains kind of conflate
two topics or two subjects so as soon as
you like can properly classify it even
as you were describing that thing that I
Gro the first time with the windows and
all that I feel like um having like just
a mental a physical mental view of what
actually is occurring I even noticed you
kind of do it when you draw it out with
your hands and you say it goes over and
then it goes down it goes in it's like
these like spatial references really
help understand frontend hacks like
front end bu so oh for sure dude for
sure yeah and that's that's why we try
to always draw it out when we're doing
the master classes the critical thinkers
Discord and stuff like that to try to
give people a tangible method you know
you got you got auditory Learners you
got visual Learners you got kid
aesthetic Learners I think we over
leverage you know on the on the
kinesthetic Learners because we're
hackers we like to get our hands on the
keyboard and tweak with stuff but um
there's a lot of people that learn by
via audio the podcast or visual you know
watching something or seeing a graph
drawn um you just got to figure out
which way you learn best and then try to
get the content into that medium for you
which is why we also release the podcast
of iot text with the hacker notes so so
people that learn better by reading can
ingest the same content and get the
value out so yeah yeah exactly and you
know using AI you can kind of swap
between those those modalities a little
bit a little bit more seamlessly these
days so yeah for sure man all right you
got anything else to add or is that a
wrap on the Pod no I think that's it I
appreciate it I'm excited um gonna go
try to find my first bug on day one of
fulltime bug Bounty so dude GG go get it
man all right peace see
you and that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking in in content head over to ctbb
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there